This is Lexi. Lexi, Kara.
Where’s Allie?
- We broke up, Lex. - [LEXI] What?
But, you know, we all saw this coming.
[LEXI] I’m sorry to say this, okay?
But it seems like you and Kara have more chemistry!
[LEXI] Okay, anyway!
- Are you okay, bro? - I got friendzoned, bro.
Don’t be sad.
[QUINITO] I’m happy for Jao.
You and Kara look good together.
I think...
Kara also likes you.
What's the status between the two of you?
We just like spending a lot of time together.
- [ARCHIE] Hi, Kara. - [KARA] Archie!
- I’ve missed you so much. - I’ve missed you!
Jao, this is Archie.
I’m Jao.
So, you’re here for vacation?
No, I’m here for Kara.
Um...
Archie, can I bring Jao along next week?
Yeah, man. Is that okay?
What made you decide to volunteer today, Quinito?
I also want to give back to the kids before I go back to Manila.
You’re leaving?
Bro, we’re really gonna miss you.
Kara told me you work for Young Horizon?
You won’t stop until you find out what I do for a living, huh?
I'm just curious, bro.
Do we have a problem?
So we’ve prepared some compost materials,
so you guys can try it yourselves.
Why don’t you just watch us...
Kara?
I’ll partner up with Jao.
[LEXI] We can be partners, bro.
Teach me.
It will be fun.
Bro.
Sure.
I don’t know anything about this.
It’s okay. Just follow my lead.
Okay.
So, let's start with dried leaves.
[KARA] Dried leaves are rich in carbon.
They’ll help balance the compost as it breaks down.
Just add more...
And this is... bok choy?
Yeah.
So just get...
Okay. Next one.
You can add some more.
Why?
It's just amazing how...
as I get to know you,
the more I discover how knowledgeable you are.
And I find your intelligence...
very attractive.
[KARA CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
Oh, please.
[JAO AND KARA CHUCKLES]
Bro, I know you don’t know me,
but I’m just saying…
That’s a lost cause.
What?
Kara and Jao!
It’s done!
You don't stand a chance.
[IMITATES EXPLOSION] None!
Just look at them.
[LEXI] Do you know what that’s called?
Which, incidentally, is happening right here, right now.
[LEXI CLAPS]
They've got chemistry, bro.
That’s chemistry.
And all you have in your hands is soil
and a bunch of crap.
[ALON BY JL]
[CHILDREN TALKING]
Hello, everyone!
- Hi! - Hi!
I’m Quinito, and today,
we’ll be reading a story by Ica!
Give her a round of applause!
[CLAPPING]
Today’s story is about...
Inoy.
“Inoy and the Waves.”
It's about the waves of Siargao
and how Inoy was swept away by them.
Okay, let’s start. Are you guys ready?
- [KIDS] Yes! - Okay.
Inoy couldn’t remember how the waves carried him
to the island of Siargao.
[QUINITO] All he knew
was that he felt lonely where he was.
And when the waves sang to him,
he followed them right away.
On the island of Siargao,
he met many friends.
Mangroves,
fish,
turtles...
But one stood out the most...
A pearl that shone as brightly as the sun.
[QUINITO] He’d been warned many times
not to go near the mysterious pearl
as its brilliant glow could burn him.
But Inoy was always stubborn.
He wanted to get to know the pearl, even if it meant getting hurt.
Do you like libraries?
Oh! Yes, Sir Han.
You can’t tell, but I'm always browsing.
Because in the library,
this is where I can see all parts of the world.
Then you should see the New York Public Library.
It’s really big!
And I think you would also enjoy the
Bodleian in Oxford.
It’s so peaceful and quiet there.
- Oh! - And...
one more library in Amsterdam,
near the harbor, which has a cafe on the rooftop…
You know, it’s really amazing.
Wow!
You know what, Sir Han?
Just hearing you describe it,
I can already picture it and I already want to go!
[HAN BIN AND PEARL LAUGH]
[PEARL] Wow, you've been to a lot of places, Sir Han.
Wait, in Korea, is there a library also?
Yeah! We also have amazing libraries in Korea, too.
You should see the...
Starfield Library in Seoul.
You’ve been to all the libraries you mentioned?
No…
I just heard all about those libraries...
from my…
…from my friend!
- Yes, from a friend. - A friend.
- Yes. - Okay.
- You want to go to the bathroom? - [QUINITO] ...And Inoy asked his friends, the waves,
to carry the pearl wherever...
it wished to go.
[QUINITO] Though his hands blistered from holding it,
he had no regrets.
To Inoy,
those blisters were a reminder of his friend, the pearl.
Goodbye, my friend, pearl.
I hope you won’t forget me.
[CLAPPING]
[QUINITO] Did you enjoy it?
[BACKGROUND CHATTER]
What should I upload?
Hm... What do you think?
This one? This?
- Nice. [PEARL LAUGHS] - Or this?
Ariel, why is...
Sir Han facing away in all your photos?
I told you, he hates photos and videos.
Why, though?
No idea. Maybe he doesn’t want to be famous.
Or maybe he doesn’t want to get hate.
Is he a celebrity or something?
[QUINITO] Good idea!
What if he really is a celebrity in Korea?
You know, someone messaged me,
looking for a Song Ji Hoon.
Who’s that?
I don’t know!
[KARA] We’ll water them later.
[LEXI] Just say the word.
I’ll take care of Archie.
You know I’ve been taking jiu-jitsu lessons?
Forget it. Just ignore him.
[LEXI SIGHS]
He’s just jealous because Kara’s obviously into you, too.
Hey, wipe that grin off your face.
Make a move!
Lex…
actually, it’s not on me.
I like Kara a lot.
But...
I have to respect her timeline.
Wow.
Slow and long courtship.
So old school!
But I love it! [LEXI GIGGLES]
[JAO] All that's missing is Harana (traditional Filipino serenade), right?
What's Harana?
What do you mean?
[JAO STUTTERS]
You’re making me feel too old.
Harana?
[LEXI SCOFFS]
[ARCHIE] Kara, I’ll just check on the guests.
- [KARA] Okay. - [LEXI] Kara!
- [LEXI] Thank you for inviting me here! - [KARA] You’re welcome!
[LEXI] You’re right. I learned a lot here.
I had fun, except…
[KARA LAUGHS]
Sorry about Archie.
He’s a little blunt.
But once you get to know him, he’s actually a nice guy.
- Nice? Him? I doubt it. - [KARA CHUCKLES]
Well, since I'm leaving anyway, whatever.
You’re not extending your stay?
No, don’t tempt me!
If I end up quitting my job, I won’t know what to do next.
Maybe I should quit?
- Anyway… - [KARA LAUGHS]
[LEXI] I have two more nights left in Siargao.
I’m going to make the most of them.
Bye, Kara!
[LEXI] It might be short and sweet,
[LEXI] but I had fun.
Yay! I’m so glad.
- [KARA AND LEXI LAUGH] - And this guy?
He’s one of the good ones.
[LEXI] Trust me. I can vouch for him.
All right, enough.
Isn’t that guy from the dating app waiting for you?
What guy? Excuse me!
We met at a beach club.
It was an organic encounter with a couple of beers
and lots of foam and bubbles!
- Okay, fine. - [LEXI] Bubbles!
Whatever you say. Go!
[JAO] You’re going to be late!
[LEXI] What’s so funny?
- Text me when you get there, okay? - [LEXI] Okay, bye!
[LEXI] Bye, Kara!
[QUINITO] The waves were awesome earlier, bro!
Yeah! It’s intense!
[QUINITO LAUGHS]
By the way, did…
Did Pearl leave early?
Yeah, she met Ariel a while ago.
[QUINITO] Hm... So...
Gaia is open today?
No, Ariel met some tourist from Manila.
They will party at El Lobo later.
Oh...
How are you, brother?
I’m cool, bro. I’m actually happy.
[HAN BIN] Oh…
I thought you’re heartbroken.
[QUINITO LAUGHS]
Maybe a little bit.
But, for real, though,
I’m actually feeling good.
[QUINITO] Even though…
[QUINITO CLICKS TONGUE]
[QUINITO SIGHS] Pearl rejected me, I feel like,
you know, there’s a reset button.
I can finally focus on my goal.
I’m happy for you, bro.
[QUINITO] Yeah, I mean...
I’m actually happy, too, that
Pearl and I are not awkward anymore.
[HAN BIN] That’s good.
But, you know,
I think I know why she…
[QUINITO CLICKS TONGUE] ...friendzoned me.
Really? Why?
Because I think she likes someone else.
You think so?
I know so, brother.
[HAN BIN WHISTLES]
[HAN BIN GRUNTS]
[HAN BIN HUMS]
[HAN BIN SIGHS]
[HAN BIN EXHALES]
[JAO] Kind of random that you brought me here.
[KARA] Not really.
I just wanted you to see Cabitoonan at sunset.
Beautiful, right?
[JAO] The magic of this place never seems to run out.
[KARA] You know, Noah and I got approval for our mangrove project.
[JAO] Wow, congratulations!
[KARA] We just need the permit.
[JAO] That means more mangroves for Siargao!
[KARA] Exactly.
What?
Nothing. It’s just that...
your smile’s prettier than the sunset.
I like seeing you like this, Kara.
I like seeing you happy.
The love you have for Siargao is really inspiring.
I’m happy that you’re here, Jao.
I’m thankful you came back.
[KARA AND JAO CHUCKLE]
[JAO SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Good morning.
What’s the occasion?
Nothing. I just wanted to give you flowers.
Should I pick you up after your tour?
Jao, I’m not used to being babied.
Nothing has to change just because...
You’re almost there, Pearl.
You have the right words.
I will finish this some other time.
I just need to get ready for our celebration later.
[HAN BIN] Good morning, guys!
[JAO] Happy anniversary!
[KARA] You see this?
They all have jobs because of you.
[SIARGAONON] Thank you very much, Han Bin.
You guys all mean so much to me.
[HAN BIN] Thank you, Kara.
[PEOPLE CHEERING]
[JAO] Wait, wait!
- Pearl, it’s beautiful, right? - Yeah.
And your story’s beautiful, too.
Tell me more, okay?
What are you even doing? Let’s go.
[MAN] Caitlyn?